Esta é a lição 28 de PEMSler Inglês 1. Você vai
ouvir uma conversa mais informal do que as que você tem escutado.
Os interlocutores vão dizer hi em vez de hello,
thanks a lot em vez de thank you very much.
Estas expressões informais são usadas com frequência na vida
diária. Listen. Hi, Katie. How are you?
Hi, Charles. I'm fine, thanks. And you?
Oh, I don't know. You know, I'm going to Boston today.
My family lives there. Would you like to go with me?
Yes, I would. Thanks a lot. Listen again.
Hi, Katie. How are you? Hi, Charles. I'm fine,
thanks. And you? Oh, I don't know. You know, I'm going to
Boston today. My family lives there. Would you like to go with me? Yes,
I would. Thanks a lot. Say in
English, juntos.
Together.
Say, nós vamos para Washington,
D.C. We're going to Washington, D.C.
Nós vamos embora juntos.
We're leaving together.
Talvez. Maybe.
Ask. Quanto dinheiro você tem?
How much money
do you have?
Answer: Eu tenho cem dólares.
I have one hundred dollars.
One hundred dollars. Say.
Eu não tenho.
I don't have any.
Ask. Você pode me dar noventa dólares?
Can you give me ninety dollars?
Answer. Eu não quero.
I don't want to.
Eu vou embora agora.
I'm leaving now.
Ask where she wants to go.
Where do you want to go?
Eu vou para Boston.
I'm going to
Boston.
Com meus amigos.
With my friends.
With my friends. How do you
say eu acho que não?
I don't think so.
Talvez. Maybe.
Sei. Eu acho que eu vou para Boston.
I think I'm going to Boston.
Eu quero ver Boston.
I want to see Boston.
Depois eu vou trabalhar.
Then I'm going to work.
E você? Você vai trabalhar?
And you, are you going to work?
Say, eu acho que não.
I don't think so.
Ask, por que não?
Why not? Why not?
Say, minha esposa quer comprar algo.
My wife wants to buy something.
Mas ela não tem dinheiro americano.
But she doesn't have any American money.
She doesn't.
She doesn't have any American money.
Ela não precisa de nada.
She doesn't need anything.
Nós não precisamos de nada.
We don't need anything.
We don't.
Mas ela gostaria de comprar algo.
But she'd like to buy something.
Para nossas crianças.
For our children.
Sei. Eu vou embora agora.
I'm leaving now.
Você pode me dar noventa e cinco dólares?
Can you give me ninety-five dollars?
Ninety-five.
Say, tudo bem. Aqui estão cem dólares.
All right. Here's one hundred dollars.
Listen. Great, thanks. Você quer perguntar
o que isso quer dizer? Listen and repeat.
What does that mean?
Mean.
That. What does that
mean?
Ask again. O que isso quer dizer?
What does that mean?
Try to ask. O que quer dizer great?
What does great mean?
A palavra great. Listen and repeat.
The word great.
Word. The word.
Say again. A palavra.
The word.
Say. A palavra great.
The word great.
Try to ask: O que quer dizer a palavra great?
What does the word great mean?
É uma palavra em inglês. Listen and repeat.
It's an English word.
An. An English
word. It's an English word.
Not a palavra an. Utiliza-se da mesma maneira que
a, mas se usa com palavras que começam com vogais,
como English, American.
Say again. É uma palavra em inglês.
It's an English word.
An English word.
Say sim. Eu acho que sim.
Yes, I think so.
O que quer dizer a palavra great?
What does the word great mean?
Now try to ask: Vocês são americanos?
Are you American?
American. Try to say: Sim, nós somos americanos.
Yes, we're American.
We are. We're American.
Now try to
say: Nós temos um carro americano.
We have an American car.
An American car.
Você percebeu como an American se juntam?
Diga outra vez: nós temos um carro americano.
We have an American car.
In English,
how do you say palavra?
Word. The word. Say the
word great.
Great.
Ask what that means. Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
Now say, nós estamos aqui.
We're here.
We're here. Nós estamos
aqui por alguns dias. Alguns dias.
Listen and repeat. A few days.
Days. Days.
A few days.
Say again. Alguns dias.
Nós estamos aqui por alguns dias. Listen and
repeat. We're here for a few days.
For. For a few days.
We're here for a few days.
A palavra for tem diversos significados em inglês.
Você já a utilizou como dar. Também pode
indicar um espaço de tempo específico, por exemplo, para dizer quanto
tempo você vai ficar no lugar. Diga outra vez: nós estamos aqui
por alguns dias.
We're here for a few days.
For a few days.
Try to ask, quantos dias?
How many
days? How many days?
Say, três ou quatro dias.
Three or four days.
Quanto tempo? Listen and repeat. How long?
Long.
Long. How long?
Ask again. Quanto tempo?
How long? Por alguns
dias. For a few days.
For a few days.
How long are you going to stay? Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
O que quer dizer stay?
What does stay mean? Stay,
कहतے ہیں فکر.
Listen and repeat. Stay means فکر.
Means means stay
means فکر.
Ah, agora eu entendo.
Oh, now I understand.
Ask again. Quanto tempo?
How long?
Now try to ask.
Quanto tempo vocês vão ficar?
How long are you going to stay?
Stay. How long
are you going to stay?
Sai por alguns dias.
For a few days.
Nós vamos ficar.
We're going to stay.
Por alguns dias.
For a few days.
Você se lembra de como se diz que horas são?
What time is it?
Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
What does time mean?
Time quer dizer tempo.
Time means tempo.
Now try to say, nós temos muito tempo.
We have a lot of time.
Nós não temos muito tempo.
We don't have a lot of time.
Say, nós vamos ficar.
We're going to
stay.
Por alguns dias.
For a few days.
Porque nós não temos muito tempo.
Because we don't have a lot of time.
Esta é outra maneira de dizer isso. Listen and repeat.
We don't have much time.
Much time.
Say that again. Say that again.
We don't have much time.
A lot of, much. Tem quase o mesmo sentido.
Mas much é mais comum quando se usa negativa.
Continue dizendo much nesta negação,
a não ser que te digam para não fazê-lo. Agora diga-me outra
vez que vocês não têm muito tempo.
We don't have much time.
Nós vamos para Boston.
We're going to Boston.
Nós vamos embora amanhã.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Juntos. Together.
Great! Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
Try to say. Eu não sei o que isso quer dizer.
I don't know what that means.
What that means. I don't
know what that means.
Now say, nosso amigo George mora em Boston.
Our friend George lives in Boston.
Ele também trabalha lá.
He works there too.
Ele não tem carro.
He doesn't have a car.
Por que não? Why not?
Why not? Ele não precisa de
He doesn't need a car.
Mas ele quer comprar um carro.
But he wants to buy a car.
Ele quer comprar um carro americano.
He wants to buy an American car.
An American car.
Say, ele precisa de um pouco de dinheiro.
He needs some money.
Some money.
Nós não precisamos de nada.
We don't need anything.
Mas nós gostaríamos de ver o nosso amigo George.
But we'd like to see our friend George.
Nós gostaríamos de ficar em Boston.
We'd like to stay in Boston.
For three days.
Ask how long. Ask how long.
How long?
Quanto tempo você vai ficar em Boston?
How long
are you going to stay in Boston?
Say, nós gostaríamos de ficar três dias,
literalmente por três dias.
We'd like to stay for three days.
We don't have
much time.
Much time.
And our friend doesn't have much time.
We can't
stay. We can't stay.
Usando por, diga: nós não podemos ficar cinco dias.
We can't stay for five days.
For five days.
Now say,
"Eu gostaria de ficar." I'd
like to stay.
Eu gostaria de ficar na América.
I'd like to stay in America.
Mas nós não temos muito tempo.
But we don't have much time.
E nós gostaríamos de ver nossos filhos.
And we'd like to see our children.
Nós vamos para Boston amanhã.
We're going to Boston tomorrow.
Try to say. E depois nós vamos ao Brasil.
And then we're going to Brazil.
To Brazil.
Juntos. Together.
Great. Ask what that means.
What does that mean?
A palavra great.
The word great.
O que quer dizer great?
What does great mean?
What does the word great mean?
Great quer dizer ótimo.
Great means ótimo.
Nesta lição de Inglês 1 se incluem exercícios de leitura.